

# ANNELISE N. SMITH

# UX DESIGN AND RESEARCH

annelisesmithux@gmail.com // anoelles.github.io

### **SKILLS**

User Research
Usability Testing
Persona Development
Card Sorting
Journey Mapping
Content Analysis
HTML/CSS
Paper Prototyping
Mobile Experience Design
Axure
Sketch
InVision
OmniGraffle
Adobe Illustrator

#### **EDUCATION**

**UX Design Immersive**General Assembly Seattle
2016

MA in Human Development Washington State University Prevention Science Track 2013

**BA in Social Sciences**Washington State University
Minors in German and
Ethnic Studies
2011

## **ABOUT ME**

I'm a UX designer and researcher with experience applying user-centered methodologies to identify core user needs and motivations, translating these insights into evidence-based designs. Armed with a creative yet analytical mind, I have a knack for quickly building genuine connections with others and I approach challenges with an enthusiasm that naturally motivates those around me.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

UX Designer // Dive Around the Clock // Seattle, WA // Oct 2016 - Dec 2016

Improve alignment of website with user needs through primary user research including interviews, usability testing, and behavioral observation; utilize IA principles and develop site maps/wireframes that enable intuitive navigation and increase click-through to donation and volunteer registration tasks; create new visual branding and style guide.

Field Marketing Specialist // Publicis Hawkeye // Seattle, WA // Oct 2015-Aug 2016

Devise, organize, and execute guerrilla marketing campaigns to drive product awareness and foster brand loyalty

Investigator // WA Child Protective Services // Tacoma, WA // Aug 2014- Oct 2015

Conduct in-home interviews and rapport-building to identify core family problems and make critical legal decisions under limited time constraints and in high-stress situations; facilitate creative solutions to child safety problems using existing family and community resources; create accurate documentation in compliance with federal mandates.

Site Coordinator // Communities in Schools // Lakewood, WA // Aug 2013- Oct 2014

Collaborate with student, family, school, and community stakeholders to identify core student needs and secure resources for at-risk students.

Research Assistant // Washington State University // Pullman, WA // Aug 2011- July 2013

Create and oversee implementation of data collection and analysis timeline; collaborate as author on scholarly publications; write research briefs and literature reviews to support evidence-based decision making; develop outcome evaluation plans for existing health promotion programs; design, implement, and evaluate social media campaigns for incoming students.